Sahil Johari

Pittsburgh PA 15219 | 214-458-7161 | sahiljohari12@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Summary of Qualifications

Offering over **2.5** years of experience in software engineering. Currently working as a Front-end Software Engineer in an agile environment, creating rewarding user interfaces for next-generation web apps using modern frameworks.

Communication | Attention to Detail | Teamwork | Creativity | Passion | Quick Learning | Curiosity | Ownership

Technical Skills

- Web Standards: HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Redux, Node, TypeScript
- Testing Frameworks: Cypress, Jest, Enzyme, rspec-rails
- Programming Languages: Python, MySQL
- Others: REST API consumption, Git/GitHub, Postman

Professional Experience

Software Engineer - Rivers Agile - Pittsburgh, PA

FiCrowd

- Provide smooth crowdfunding solutions by developing over-the-top product features fulfilling the customers' requirements
- Revamp the user interface to enhance users' crowdfunding experience by implementing effective and aesthetically pleasing UI styling techniques
- Streamline application development effort and code reusability by reorganizing the front-end code into robust and maintainable UI components
- Technologies Used: Angular 9, Bootstrap 4, CSS3, Node, AWS (Lambda, Cognito)

IBM Pittsburgh Lab August 2019 – May 2020

- Develop, using wireframes, fully functional front-end UI components of *Discovery Tooling* a user facing online tool in IBM Watson™ Discovery, with 48 user stories completed
- Successfully completed and deployed over 18 user stories/features for product release in November 2019
- Developed and owned the conversational feature (**Chat Bot**) using *Discovery API* to provide intuitive responses to user queries
- Improved testability, maintainability, and code readability by migrating over 30 integration tests from *rspec-rails* to *Cypress* framework
- Technologies Used: React, Redux, TypeScript, SASS, Node, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress

Senior Analyst - Capgemini Technology Services India Limited - India

Jetstar Airways Pty Ltd.

June 2015 - June 2017

May 2020 - Present

- Reduced the lead time by 80% for the customer via generating and distributing over 125 reports by developing an automation web application using .NET framework
- Redesigned and implemented UI for a legacy application to offer improved aesthetics and user experience using jQuery and Bootstrap
- Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3, jQuery, ASP.NET, C#, Oracle PL-SQL

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

May 2019 GPA: 3.53/4.0

June 2015

Additional Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant

January 2019 - April 2019

GPA: 70.13% (Final Year)

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Southern Methodist University - Dallas, Texas

- Course: Principles of Computer Science
- Instructed undergraduate students on hands-on programming sessions in Java conducted for a span of 8 weeks